# **Ahmed Nasif Shahriar**

2 Eastern Blvd Leicester LE27PT | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/username/ | Email:

ahmedshahriar12@gmail.com | **Phone**: 0743845010 Portfolio (GitHub link) : https://github.com/Nasif4567

#### **PROFILE**

Undergraduate Software Engineering student currently studying in second year at DMU. I have 2+ year experience over full stack Java programming & android application development (Java). 1+ year experience in Web development, mobile application (Flutter, Java) and python. Seeking placement in organization has following technologies (Java SE, Java EE, Spring) where my technical skill and interpersonal skill can be demonstrated for the success of the company.

#### **EDUCATION**

**De Montfort university,** Leicester, UK Software Engineering BSc (Hons)

Sep 2022 - Present

## Degree Year 2 module

Data Structure and Algorithm Web development Object Oriented Design Software management and security

**Asia pacific university of innovation and technology**, Kuala Lampur ,Malaysia Diploma in ICT with specialism in Software Engineering | CGPA: 2.73

Nov 2018 - Jan 2021

## Diploma year 1 and 2 modules

Java programming
Operating System
System Analysis
Computer System -Architecture
Visual Basic .Net
Network and Networking
Discrete Mathematics
Numeric methods
Academic research skill
Professional communication

International Education Centre, Dhaka, Bangladesh

GCSE: Graded 6 B's and one C in 7 subjects

Jun 2009 - May 2018

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Gao Tek, Remote (United States)
Role: Digital Marketing Intern

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

Conducted research on SEO keyword finding

APIIT corporate training, Kuala Lampur, Malaysia

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

## **Role: Software Engineering Intern**

- Contributed to the team by making Java documentation of the code
- Supported by testing java code's method using JUnit and fixing the portion of the code hence made

- the overall task quicker through my contribution
- Involved in making videos and doing research on company's micro credential program marketing and was able to make 2 customer join the program
- Co-ordinated the team and created daily reports and weekly report on team progress

#### **PROJECTS**

- Retailer management system Developed the admin's system and customer's system using java
- Hospital management system android application Developed using Java and SQL Lite database
- Al Budget Planner android application –also developed using java and firebase cloud database
- Online store bakery shop (admin and customer system) Developed using PHP, JavaScript, HTML and MySQL database
- E- Learning system Developed whole system using Visual Basic. Net and MS Access database
- Contributed (Font- end programming) to an E-commerce site called Dandelion HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Uniform detection system Developed using python
- My portfolio GitHub link : <a href="https://github.com/Nasif4567">https://github.com/Nasif4567</a> -----All my projects can be found here

## **SKILLS**

- Expert in Java SE, Java EE (Servlet JSP JSF Web services): 2+ year experience on it, expert in using the language for developing application and developed projects with it in my software projects, internship and on university modules.
- Framework (Spring core Spring MVC Spring security String restful)
- Database (MySQL, Firebase, Mongo DB): Good Knowledge of these database programming and familiar with integrating these database with the project's systems
- Android Application development (Java): 2+ year experience on it, developed two mobile application using java in android studio.
- Testing application using JUnit: Tested java methods during internship also degree module
- Web technologies (HTML5 CSS- JavaScript AJAX Express): Expert in both, font-end using HTML5, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript and backend using Node JavaScript.
- **PHP**: 1+ Year experience on it, did backend programming of website projects for secure data manipulation.
- Python (Not major): Developed 1 project
- Visual basic .NET: Developed Window's desktop application using visual studio during diploma modules
- Flutter (For basic mobile application)
- **Team work and communication**: Ability to interact professionally with others in the workplace and in other environments. Been doing team work in diploma modules, internship, projects and degree modules.
- Research and Making technical Documentation Been doing research and making technical documents in diploma modules, degree modules and also internship.
- Excellent IT Software knowledge (MS Office)
- Problem solving Enhanced through doing projects, issues at work and university modules

#### Reference

Available upon request